Rafael Turse Wenceslau Ribeiro

Downtown Toronto - ON, M5J 2Z3 +1 (647) 505-8508 rafaelturse@hotmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rafaelturse | github.com/rafaelturse

Software Engineer

Software engineer since 2011, postgraduate in Mobile Application Development with strengths in Java, Spring, Kotlin, Android, JavaScript, React, Node, and SQL. Analytical thinker with a positive work ethic, adaptability, organizational skills, and a proactive learning approach. Excels in multitasking, problem-solving, and decision-making.

Work Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer at BrainyYack

(12/2022 - 02/2023)

- Directed Xemoto project, applying Scrum methodology and GitLab pipeline, leading development efforts across frontend, backend, and database. Contributed significantly to the implementation of new features and APIs using Kotlin, Java, React, JavaScript, Node, and PostgreSQL.
- Developed and debugged web applications using Java, Kotlin, Spring, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Gradle, Docker, PostgreSQL, GitLab, Postman, IntelliJ, Figma, Jira, and Asana, resulting in enhanced functionality and seamless user experiences.

WordPress Developer at *Express Gold Refining*

(01/2022 - 06/2022)

 Enhanced user experience on the company's website through frontend customization, implemented new features and resolved bugs in WordPress and WooCommerce templates using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL.

Software Engineer at *Fundação Carlos Chagas*

(04/2019 - 12/2019)

- Collaborated with the backend development team to optimize registration processes for public tenders, developed new features, and renovated code for improved system stability and usability.
- Led projects involving public tender portals and billing generation systems, utilizing Java, JSP, Mentawai, MySQL, Eclipse, Java 8, Spring Boot, Microservices, Spring Cloud, Eureka Server, Zuul API Gateway, JSON, Postman, Jenkins, GitLab, and Tomcat.

Software Developer at *Samsung SDS Cello Logistics*

(10/2018 - 04/2019)

- Managed backend web application development with Java 8, JSF, Primefaces, Hibernate Criteria, JPQL,
 Oracle SQL Developer, SVN, Maven Quartz, WildFly, and Eclipse.
- Key projects comprised the creation of Mais Brasil, an independent application designed for batch processing files, and Samsung WMS, where novel features were implemented to enhance supply chain and warehouse management systems.

Education

Postgraduate in Mobile Application Development at *George Brown College* (09/2023 - 09/2024) The focus of the program is the two main platforms on mobile devices: iOS and Android. Coding is conducted in the Kotlin and Swift programming languages, which are supported by both their adjacent technologies and other technologies such as HTML 5, CSS3, SQL and JavaScript, as well as their client-side, server-side and onboard programming aspects.